I would like to we have about a half
hour before friends have to some friends
have to leave we require for you what
you told me 10 ACOG you cheat me again
ok 9:45 yeah ok 13 minutes to finish the
gardener I can do it with no stress I
can do
[Laughter]
we finished three and a half chapter ok
I don't forget I owe you two and a half
more chapters right don't worry I didn't
forget but we did them correctly and we
did them slow so you got that Tim I'm
going to show you the first minute ok
Tim I have a video ok can you turn on
the projector cool ok the first chapter
that we studied was an erection of the
indriyas of the eye and the object ok so
there's a cute video that I I often
enjoy ok there's a what's it called
Heisman uncertainty principle Heisenberg
uncertainty principle it means a there's
a problem in quantum physics with how we
see things there's a problem how light
comes from the Sun to the earth ok
there's a problem and Stephen Hawking
couldn't figure it out but we figured it
out ok so here's the problem you ready
and I'm not going to show the whole
thing Oh money baby home
quantum mean weird the guys are weird
[Music]
okay this is Nagaya it doesn't make
sense and still in quantum physics we
still don't know how does the sunlight
reach the earth you know we will die
without the Sun we will have no food we
will have no suntan and how does it come
from the Sun we don't know okay how does
it come from the Sun this is chapter
three he's teaching chapter three how
does it come from the Sun good say it
louder
four zero dollars
a see that comes from my mind opens and
it creates me and the sunlight reaching
the earth okay got it got it
how did the Sun light come to this earth
it's C opening in your mind okay how
does food grow from the Sun crops it's
coming from you okay so that covers
chapter three we finished chapter three
chapter four what wasn't examination of
the state of Sanskrit no examination of
prediction of Skanda right examine the
five parts of the person right so for
this we can what's weird about elements
right and the results of the elements
what's weird about them is aspirin okay
aspirin it has a chemical inside and
then when we get a headache
our mom tada you're I'm I remember my
mom told me take a husband if you get I
used to get very bad headaches when I'm
a kid and my mom will say oh just take a
spin and then I remember one day nothing
happened I remember which bed I'm in my
brother's bed I couldn't even go to my
room I couldn't reach my room and I'm in
my brother's bed
she gave me a spin nothing happened
then I asked mom I called my mom it
didn't work I still have a headache she
said I would take a second one then I'd
take a second one you know 10 minutes
later it's still staying honey you know
then I called my mom my mom I need a
other Aspen
then she I remember she pick up the
bottle and she said it's a only two for
kids only two she said I'm sorry you you
cannot have another one I said but mom I
still have a head
she said then she said a very bad bad
bad thing she said sometimes you just
have to have him and I'm like oh then we
always believe our mom we always be okay
mom she says sometimes the Aspen work
and sometimes the Aspen don't work
okay honey it's like that life is like
that
she lied to me okay she was a bad
plumber she didn't tell me the truth
okay she didn't understand negara
chapter four she believed that when he
come to kinds of atoms in the molecule
in the aspirin she believed in okay
there's two kinds of atoms in the
molecule she believed it Aspen has a
special atoms Aspen has a special
molecules okay she believed it okay
understand so that's a second example
that's Chapter four we want a real
example gala we want real example okay
what was Chapter three
sunlight how it reached the earth what
was chapter four aspirin was Chapter
five
yes base and the definition of space and
luck China on the fire stays the hot and
burning
nobody glue it nobody took the heart and
burning and put it on the fire it's
latina it's a sign of that thing it's
the sign of that thing that's Chapter
five okay then fire is not coming the
heart of fire if not coming what's a
practical use what's a practical use
then I remember I gave this teaching in
New York just before my three-year
between then it was very difficult
I taught 18 HCI courses
it was very difficult I made an
announcement I'm leaving New York then
everyone's like wow yeah I remember I
stood up I said I'm leaving New York I
have to go you know and I'm doing three
or between in Arizona in the desert and
everyone and I said I will give one more
teaching at the World Trade Center we
went to the World Trade Center you
either and I gave the teaching at the
bottom of the world chichén and I said
the steel in this building has lection
er right it's hard and it can hold up
the big building right what's holding up
the World Trade Center is the steel and
inside it has luck you know hard strong
hard and strong right know that hardens
I remember I gave this talk last thing I
did in New York it's not steep it's not
the lacuna it's not the hard and it see
and it's not hard and it's not the
strong is in the steel okay it's not the
hard and this chunk is in the steel okay
what's keeping up this roof is it the
walls yeah your karma your sins okay
your seats to keep up this roof it's not
the bricks okay forget it they're not
doing it don't think like that if you
want to have a roof over your head we
say in English if you want to have a
apartment if you want to have a place to
stay you must do the 13-step Tolan on
other people you must give them places
to stay and if you don't that building
will fall down what happened yeah I went
into 303 you know
and I remember there were many military
planes suddenly we are in the middle of
the desert
then suddenly many planes practicing
juju uh you know we are like out here
you know and yeah what's going on you
know we don't know then when we came out
of retreat that newspaper came the big
newspaper Benson it has three pages and
they came to interview us they said you
are the only people in the world who
don't know
and we said what they said world
transcendent fell down I'm like oh yeah
okay okay I understand now last one then
you guys can go I still have 30 circuits
okay Stanley when the wife come in the
kitchen and the man start to yeah
husband start to yeah I imagine okay
there's a yo Chow on the table what
happens when you feel stressed at home
sometimes you eat too much that's why we
did fine you know with too much stress
even Geshe Michael when he go home at
night last night I ate three bowls of
cereal before go to bed because I'm
tired then the wife also think Oh
husband is not nice to me
I have to eat something to feel happy
you know the yo cha will make me happy
okay listen the gardener doesn't like it
the your town will make me happy he's
like which part of the hotel where the
first touch my tongue Oh does it touch
the tongue yeah time to tell me your
tongue no it doesn't the in front of
that your child has a tongue where it is
the front of the hotel touch the front
of the not possible and it's very that's
the rest of chapter
six okay
the sugar crystal never touched the
tongue okay if they touch they have to
go into each other like this you see
they cannot touch like this okay if they
touch then a little bit of the sugar has
to become a little bit of the tongue you
see I understand then the sugar have to
become the tongue it's not possible okay
oh well what if the sugar doesn't become
the tongue well then they cannot affect
each other
okay cannot understand if the sugar can
give tasted the tongue without mixing
then the pupu also will give taste to
the tongue because they also don't mix
understand that this special poopoo
treasure-house the white one everything
inside will give you good taste
why gets like why you say that because
the sugar give you good taste
well no the sugars in my mouth no the
sugar is not in your mouth it cannot
touch no it touch if it touch it cover
each other if it touch them mix if you
touch them mix understand then for sugar
to give you good taste to the wife in
the kitchen because she's nervous right
the husband yell at her right if the
sugar give the taste there has to be a
little mix there has to be a little mix
if there's no mix then the poopoo in the
bathroom also gives a good taste at the
same time because they also don't mix
the poopoo also don't mix with the
tongue and that sugar they also don't
mix with the tongue
so everything that don't mixed with the
tongue should give the taste garden or
if they do mix then the tiny sugar it's
not possible it's the same as the
professor in the cartoon he's like it's
not possible that the wife can feel
better by eating the note ah it's not
not possible it's impossible okay last
question then you have to go Timmy has
to make him nothing maybe why does the
wife feel more when he called comfort
after the husband angry and go away if
she eat yo tell why Geshe Michael eat
three bowls of sweet cereal last night
why why she wants to eat she she wants
to feel relaxed she wants comfort
husband is angry haha I need some your
tongue you know I need some I need
something sweet it's too much dress so
she ain't right does the hotel give the
sweet taste no does the yota give the
Comfort what gives the Comfort 13-step
no man 13-step don't man okay then that
karma come to you through the OTO garden
later you don't need the yoga you can be
skinny and you can feel good about your
husband okay
that's how we use those four chapters
okay that's how use the four chapters
okay it's not Timmy use them where use
them in the tomlin use them in the
thirteenth steps okay in the gardener
and the tongue man got married this
morning understand okay Tim